// Introduction to computer.
var ITC_MCQS = {
  mcq1: [
    {
      id: "1",
      subject_name: "ITC",
      chapter_name: "Introduction",
      question: "Which tool is used to find a similar word in a document?",
      option_one: "Find and Replace",
      option_two: "Dictionary",
      option_three: "Thesaurus",
      option_four: "Finder",
      answer: "C",
      explanation:
        "",
    },
  ],
  mcq2: [{
     id: '2',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which language is close to human language?',
  option_one: ' High-Level language',
  option_two: 'Low-Level language',
  option_three: 'Machine language',
  option_four: 'Programming language',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq3: [{
     id: '3',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'CBT is an abbreviation for?',
  option_one: 'Computer-Based Technology',
  option_two: 'Computer Based Trading',
  option_three: 'Computer Based Training',
  option_four: 'None Of These',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq4: [{
     id: '4',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'A virus which isself-replicate itself and spread across network is called?',
  option_one: 'Bomb',
  option_two: 'Hoax',
  option_three: 'Bug',
  option_four: 'Worm',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq5: [{
     id: '5',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'IDE is an abbreviation for?',
  option_one: 'Integrated Dual Environment',
  option_two: 'Integrated Development Environment',
  option_three: 'Inter Development Environment',
  option_four: 'Inter Dual Environment',
  answer: 'B',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq6: [{
     id: '6',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: '________ is a condition created within a database or data storage technology in which the same piece of data is held in two separate places.',
  option_one: 'Data Inconsistency',
  option_two: 'Data Dependence',
  option_three: 'Data Redundancy',
  option_four: 'None of These',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq7: [{
     id: '7',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Conio.h is an abbreviation for?',
  option_one: 'Common input output',
  option_two: 'complex input output',
  option_three: 'Character input output',
  option_four: 'console input output',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq8: [{
     id: '8',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: '__________ refers to the way data is stored in a file.',
  option_one: 'File organization',
  option_two: 'Data Distribution strategy',
  option_three: 'Indexes',
  option_four: 'Integrity constraints',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq9: [{
     id: '9',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which of the following is a collection of rules for writing programs in a programming language?',
  option_one: 'Program Standards',
  option_two: 'Program logic',
  option_three: 'Syntax',
  option_four: 'None of These',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq10: [{
     id: '10',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'SQL stands for?',
  option_one: 'Simple Query Language',
  option_two: 'Sequential Query Language',
  option_three: 'Structured Query Language',
  option_four: 'None of These',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq11: [{
     id: '11',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'An electronic tool that allows information to be input, processed, and output is called _______________. ',
  option_one: 'OS',
  option_two: 'Motherboard',
  option_three: 'Computer',
  option_four: 'CPU',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq12: [{
     id: '12',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: '____________ is a worldwide network of computers.',
  option_one: 'CPU',
  option_two: 'Internet',
  option_three: 'RAM',
  option_four: 'Network',
  answer: 'B',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq13: [{
     id: '13',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Part of a computer that allows a user to put information into the computer is called ______________. ',
  option_one: 'output unit',
  option_two: 'input unit',
  option_three: 'pressing unit',
  option_four: 'communication unit',
  answer: 'B',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq14: [{
     id: '14',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which of the following produces the best qality graphics reproduction?',
  option_one: 'Laser Printer',
  option_two: 'Ink jet printer',
  option_three: 'Plotter',
  option_four: 'Do matrix printer',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq15: [{
     id: '15',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'A translator which takes assembly language program as input & produce machine language code as output?',
  option_one: 'Compiler',
  option_two: 'Interpreter',
  option_three: 'Debugger',
  option_four: 'Assembler',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq16: [{
     id: '16',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'When was Pascaline invented?',
  option_one: '1617',
  option_two: '1620',
  option_three: '1642',
  option_four: '1837',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: 'Pascals calculator is a mechanical calculator invented by Blaise Pascal in 1642'
  },],
  mcq17: [{
     id: '17',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Computer system comprises of major units',
  option_one: 'input and output',
  option_two: 'storage',
  option_three: 'processing',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq18: [{
     id: '18',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'The value of each bead in heaven is',
  option_one: '1',
  option_two: '3',
  option_three: '5',
  option_four: '7',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: 'In an abacus, each bead in heaven has a value of 5 units, while each bead on earth has a value of 1 unit.'
  },],
  mcq19: [{
     id: '19',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'In order to play and hear sound on a computer, one needs:',
  option_one: 'A sound card and speaker',
  option_two: 'A microphone',
  option_three: 'Both A and B',
  option_four: 'None of them',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq20: [{
     id: '20',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Hard disk is coated in both sides with',
  option_one: 'Magnetic metallic oxide',
  option_two: 'Optical metallic oxide',
  option_three: 'Carbon layer',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: 'n disk manufacturing, a thin coating is deposited on both sides of the substrate, mostly by a vacuum deposition process called magnetron sputtering. And it is coated with Magnetic metallic oxide'
  },],
  mcq21: [{
     id: '21',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Offline device is',
  option_one: 'A device which is not connected to CPU',
  option_two: 'A device which is connected to CPU',
  option_three: 'A direct acces storage device',
  option_four: 'An !/O device',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq22: [{
     id: '22',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'The first general purpose electronic digital computer in the world was',
  option_one: 'UNIVAC',
  option_two: 'EDVAC',
  option_three: 'ENIAC',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq23: [{
     id: '23',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'The digital computer was developed primarily in',
  option_one: 'USSR',
  option_two: 'Japan',
  option_three: 'USA',
  option_four: 'UK',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq24: [{
     id: '24',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'The number of records contained with ',
  option_one: '',
  option_two: '',
  option_three: '',
  option_four: '',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq25: [{
     id: '25',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'High level language is also called',
  option_one: 'Problem oriented language',
  option_two: 'business oriented language',
  option_three: 'Mathematially oriented language',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq26: [{
     id: '26',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Raw facts and figures about any particular topic are',
  option_one: 'Information',
  option_two: 'facts',
  option_three: 'data',
  option_four: 'none of the above',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq27: [{
     id: '27',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'One of the main feature that distanguish microprocessor from micro-computer is?',
  option_one: 'Words are usually large in microprocessors',
  option_two: 'Words are shorter in microprocessors',
  option_three: 'Microprocessor does not contain 1/0 device',
  option_four: 'Exactly the same as the machine cycle time',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq28: [{
     id: '28',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'An application program that helps the uer to change any number and immediatly see the result of that change',
  option_one: 'Desktop publishing program',
  option_two: 'Database',
  option_three: 'Spreadsheet',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq29: [{
     id: '29',
  subject_name: 'ITC',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which of the following is not a feature of first generation computers',
  option_one: 'They used vaccum tubes or values as main electronic component',
  option_two: 'The consumed lots of electricity and producted excessive heat',
  option_three: 'They used machine launguage and assembly language to program the machine',
  option_four: 'None of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
}